Guide to the Hans Bethe papers, ca. 1931-1995
Bethe, Hans papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hans Bethe papers, [ca. 1931]-1995
14-22-976
Hans Albrecht Bethe, 1906-2005
76.2 cubic feet.; 9 videocassettes; 1 videodisc; 4 reel-to-reel tapes; 7 cassette tapes.
Academic papers, notes, correspondence, administrative documents, course materials, reports, memoranda, phonograph album, articles, reprints, lectures, textbooks, reviews of professional writings, Ph.D. theses, posters, videocassettes, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of Hans Albrecht Bethe, physicist, Cornell University professor of physics, Nobel laureate. Materials relate to Bethe's work concerning nuclear physics, solar, stellar, and nuclear energy, radiation, conduction in metals, and quantum mechanics; also the administration of the Cornell University Physics Department, and Cornell courses. Collection includes material on arms and arms control, underwater explosion research, the nuclear test ban, the Strategic Defense Initiative, the hydrogen bomb and the anti-ballistic missile, the end of the Cold War, and supernovae.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Hans Albrecht Bethe (1906-2005) was among the most prominent physicists of the twentieth century, most famous for his work on the Manhattan Project during World War II, and for his Nobel prize-winning work on solar energy (1967).
Physicist, Cornell University professor of physics, Nobel laureate.
Born in Strasbourg, Bethe studied physics at Frankfurt and under Arnold Sommerfeld at the University of Munich. In 1930 he received a fellowship to Cambridge. He began his professional career at universities in Germany, and also worked with Enrico Fermi in Rome in the early 1930's. Although Bethe did not consider himself a Jew, his mother had Jewish ancestry, and thus he was removed from his university position at Tuebingen under the Nuremberg laws once Hitler came to power. He emigrated first to a position at Manchester, and then to Cornell University in 1935, where he would teach for the rest of his career.
In his early years at Cornell, Bethe formulated his theory of how stars produce energy, an achievement that would win him the Nobel Prize in 1967. Further notable accomplishments included his work on the Lamb Shift, his famous three-part summary of nuclear physics, and his post-retirement collaboration with Gerry Brown on supernovae and neutrinos.
During World War II, he headed the Theoretical Division at Los Alamos National Laboratory as part of the Manhattan Project to build the atomic bomb. Despite his concerns about escalating the nuclear arms race, he assisted in the development of the Hydrogen bomb in the 1950's. Through these experiences, he became a vocal adversary of the nuclear arms race and control, opposing programs such as the Strategic Defense Initiative, and arguing in favor of anti-proliferation and test ban treaties, including SALT I and II. He was also an impassioned supporter of nuclear power as a solution to American energy needs. He was involved in policy throughout his adult life, as a science advisor to several presidents, as someone who frequently testified before Congress on issues of scientific importance, and as an advocate for the role of scientists in public affairs.
He also performed extensive consulting work for the U.S. government and American labs, such as the Los Alamos National Laboratory (LANL), the Argonne National Laboratory (ANL) and the Oakridge and Lawrence Livermore Laboratories. He also did consulting work for businesses such as Avco. Such consulting work generally related either to nuclear energy, or to defense.
After immigrating to the United States, he reconnected with Rose Ewald, daughter of his earlier physics mentor, Peter Paul Ewald. They married in 1939, and had two children, Henry and Monica. He retired from Cornell in 1975, but continued his astrophysics research and continued to be an expert on thermonuclear processes, shock waves, and neutrino reactions.
Bethe died at age 98 in 2005, having continued to participate in scientific study and policy until late in his life.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers consist of Bethe's calculations, notes, and correspondence with colleagues concerning nuclear physics, solar, stellar, and nuclear energy, radiation, conduction in metals, quantum mechanics, the recommendation of physicists for various positions and grants, administration of the Cornell University Physics Department, Cornell courses, arms and arms control, underwater explosion research, nuclear test ban, and other topics; reports and hearings of the Atomic Energy Commission; Navy research reports; President's Science Advisory Committee memoranda; phonograph album of a television interview with Bethe concerning scientific education in the United States; articles, reprints, lectures, and textbooks by Bethe and others; reviews of professional writings; Ph.D. theses from the Cornell Physics Department; an engraving and two posters of Bethe used to advertise the Lauritsen Memorial Lecture for 1980; and correspondence received when Bethe won the Nobel Prize. Collection includes material on Strategic Defense Initiative, the H-Bomb and the Anti-Ballistic Missile, the end of the Cold War, and supernovae. Correspondents include Kenneth T. Bainbridge, Niels Bohr, Gregory Breit, Lee A. DuBridge, George Gamow, R. Clifton Gibbs, Emil J. Konopinski, Sigurd Kohler, Irving Langmuir, Ernest O. Lawrence, Edwin M. McMillan, Carleton Murdock, Lothar W. Nordheim, J. Robert Oppenheimer, George B. Pegram, Isidor I. Rabi, Morris E. Rose, Bruno Rossi, Harlow Shapley, Eugene Paul Wigner, Robert Wilson, and Victor Weisskopf.
Records created or assembled by Hans Bethe. The collection includes correspondence; drafts and copies of Bethe's articles; articles and publications gathered for his research; notes and calculations; material related to arms control and nuclear energy advocacy, including copies of congressional testimony; meeting minutes and memoranda related to Cornell University and the physics department, and material assembled for teaching, such as overhead transparencies; clippings; transcripts of oral history interviews; and material relating to Bethe's consulting work, including memoranda from the President's Science Advisory Committee and Navy research reports.
His research topics include nuclear physics, astrophysics, radiation, quantum mechanics, and metal conduction. Other topics include policy, and materials related to the history of physics and science, including research, biographies of other physics luminaries, and interviews with Bethe. Some Bethe interviews are printed, five are on videocassette, and one is on a phonograph.
While material in the collection dates back to the 1930's, the bulk of it dates from 1950-2000. Bethe actually assembled some of the earlier material later. For instance, he later collected photocopies of his old letters from the 1930's, some of which were photocopied from other archives.
Also, five videocassettes: "An Evening with Hans Bethe: The German A-Bomb Project"; "A Conversation with Emeritus Professor Dr. Hans Bethe and Dr. Victor Weisskopf"; "A Conversation with Emeritus Professors Dr. Hans Bethe and Dr. Robert Wilson"; and, "Hans Bethe: Super Nova Mechanism," and "'I can do that!' - Hans Bethe's First 60 Years at Cornell." Includes a photograph of Bethe, Day, Long et al at the groundbreaking for Newman Laboratory, and a photograph of Bethe with Peter Carruthers and Carson Mark near Los Alamos, circa 1980.
Ten audio recordings, including Fermi Memoriam Session Remarks, 29 April 1955; Hans Bethe, introduced by Norris Bradbury (2 reels), n.d.; Physics Lecture, 7 May 1976 (1 cassette); "The Energy Problem I: The Crisis is Real," 17 May 1976; "The Energy Problem: The Necessity of Nuclear Power," 19 May 1976; and Loeb Lecture, "Reversing the Nuclear Arms Race," 11 November 1982; and "A Talk with Hans Bethe," WSKG, 30 March 1995.
Also, packet celebrating life of Hans A. Bethe containing booklet "Hans Bethe, 1906-2005," DVD "Remembering Hans Bethe," three programs, one news release; movie film, "The Nobel Prize in Physics in 1967."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bethe, Hans A.1906-2005.; Bainbridge, Kenneth T.(Kenneth Tompkins), 1904-1996.; Bohr, Niels, 1885-1962.; Breit, Gregory, 1899-1981.; Brown, G. E.(Gerald Edward), 1926-; Brueckner, Keith A.; Carruthers, Peter A., 1935-1997.; Cohen, Bernard.; Dimotakis, Paul.; DuBridge, Lee A.(Lee Alvin), 1901-1994.; Ewald, Paul Peter, 1888-1985; Feynman, Richard P.(Richard Phillips), 1918-1988.; Fowler, William A.; Gamow, George, 1904-1968.; Gibbs, R. C.(Roswell Clifton), b. 1878.; Heisenberg, Werner, 1901-1976.; Kohler, Sigurd.; Konopinski, Emil Jan, 1911-; Langmuir, Irving, 1881-1957.; Lawrence, Ernest Orlando, 1901-1958.; Lovins, Amory B., 1947-; Mark, Carson.; McMillan, Edwin M.(Edwin Mattison), 1907-; McNamara, Robert S., 1916-2009.; Murdock, Carleton C.(Carleton Chase), b. 1884.; Negele, John W..; Nomoto, Kanʾichi, 1937-; Nordheim, Lothar, 1899-; Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967.; Pegram, George Braxton, 1876-1958.; Peierls, Rudolf E.(Rudolf Ernst), 1907-1995; Rabi, I. I.(Isidor Isaac), 1898-1988.; Rose, Morris Edgar, 1911-; Rossi, Bruno Benedetto, 1905-; Salpeter, Edwin E.; Schweber, S. S.(Silvan S.); Shapley, Harlow, 1885-1972.; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951.; Sudoplatov, Pavel, 1907-1996.; Teller, Edward, 1908-2003.; Weisskopf, Victor Frederick, 1908-2002.; Wigner, Eugene Paul, 1902-1995.; Wilson, Robert R., 1914-2000.; Woosley, Stanford E.; Americans for Energy Independence.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.; Cornell University.Dept. of Physics.; Federation of American Scientists.; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission.; United States.President's Science Advisory Committee.
Titles:
Nobel Prize winners.
Subjects:
Astrophysics.; Anti-missile missiles.; Arms control.; College teachers.; Metals.; Nuclear energy.; Nuclear explosions.; Nuclear nonproliferation.; Nuclear physics--Research.; Nuclear weapons--Testing.; Physics--Study and teaching.; Physicists.; Quantum theory.; Radiation.; Science and state--United States.; Solar energy--Research.; Strategic Defense Initiative.; Supernovae.
Form and Genre Terms:
Reviews.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 61-66, 69-72, and 76-107 are restricted to permission of the archivist.
IMPORTANT: The collection is made up of two separate additions. They each have their own series lists. Similar material may be found in each portion of the collection. This means that if you are interested in Bethe's research for instance, you should browse both the series labeled research in the first part of the collection and the second part of the collection.
THE SERIES LIST FOR FIRST PORTION OF THE COLLECTION IS JUST BELOW
LINK TO THE SERIES LIST FOR SECOND PORTION OF THE COLLECTION
LINK TO THE START OF THE BOX LIST FOR FIRST PORTION OF THE COLLECTION
LINK TO THE START OF THE BOX LIST FOR SECOND PORTION OF THE COLLECTION
See also Internet-First University Press Collection, #6746, for more DVDs.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Unsorted folders primarily contain correspondence.
RELATED MATERIALS
Electronic resources/ related resources including Hans Bethe: celebrating "an exemplary life:" http://ecommons.library.cornell.edu/handle/1813/14146.
SERIES LIST FOR FIRST PORTION OF THE COLLECTION
Series I. Teaching
Courses
Boxes 61, 62, 69, 73, 76, 79, 82
Exams
Box 61
Students
Boxes 61, 79, 87, 90, 92
Physics Department
Boxes 65, 67, 77, 83, 87, 90, 92, 95, 96
Faculty Appointments/Promotions
Boxes 82, 87, 93
Post-doctoral Fellowship Applicants
Boxes 87-89
Cornell University Information
Boxes 83, 87, 89
Series II. Research
Grant Proposals
Boxes 96-97
Notes and Calculations
Boxes 61-64, 66, 68, 76, 78, 79, 85, 89, 94, 97
Graphs, Tables, Diagrams, etc.
Boxes 62, 63, 87, 89
Nuclear Matter
Boxes 66, 68, 79, 93, 95
Pions
Box 79
Solar Neutrinos
Box 97
Supernovae
Boxes 79, 87, 89, 95, 97-99
Series III. Works
Papers/Articles
Boxes 62-65, 68, 76, 78-79, 87-92, 95-96
Books
Box 73
Oral Presentations
Boxes 63, 65, 68, 73, 76, 78-79, 84, 86, 96-97
Series IV. Subject Files
Anti-Ballistic Missiles (ABM)
Boxes 65, 67-68, 80-81
Arms Control
Boxes 77, 82, 85-86, 93, 97, 99
Union of Concerned Scientists (UCS)
Boxes 77, 95, 97
Atomic Power Development Associates, Inc. (APDA)
Boxes 66-67
Atomic Energy Commission (AEC)
Box 67
Atomic Power Development Associates (APDA)
Box 67
AVCO-Everett Research Laboratory
Boxes 67, 81, 87
Fulbright Fellowship, 1955-56
Box 83
Nuclear Energy
Boxes 81-82, 90, 93
Controls on Atomic Energy
Box 82
Nuclear Testing/Test Ban
Boxes 64-65, 67-68, 77, 82, 93
Nuclear Winter
Box 82
Strategic Defense Initiative (SDI, "Star Wars")
Boxes 80, 82, 87, 93
Miscellaneous
Boxes 65, 67-68, 72, 77, 82, 87, 93, 95-97
Series V. Correspondence
General Correspondence
Boxes 65, 67-69, 76-78
Correspondence - Alphabetical
Boxes 67-72, 82-83, 85, 87, 89-90, 93-95, 97
Correspondence - Chronological
Boxes 68-69, 78, 82-83, 86, 93, 95
Series VI. Awards/Honoraria
Awards
Boxes 62-63, 67, 78, 95, 97
Nobel Prize (1967)
Boxes 68, 76, 96
Honoraria
Boxes 76, 79, 100
Series VII. Works by Others
Papers/Articles/Lectures
Boxes 62-63, 66, 68, 76-79, 82, 84, 87-90, 92-93, 95-97
Books
Boxes 65, 74-75
Series VIII. Miscellaneous
Personal
Boxes 65, 67-68, 85-88, 90, 93-94, 109
General
Boxes 65-69, 76, 82-87, 89-93, 95-97, 99
Unsorted Files
Boxes 83-97, 101-1089
Series IX. Videocassettes/DVD's
SERIES LIST FOR SECOND ADDITION TO THE COLLECTION
Series I. Research
General
Notes and Calculations
Bethe's Articles
Research by Others
Talks
Series II. Policy
General
Energy
Arms Control
Series III. Consulting
General and Arms
Energy
Series IV. Cornell
General Cornell University
Physics Department
Series V. Correspondence
By Name or Topic
Additional Correspondence Alphabetical by Letter
Additional Correspondence By Year
Additional Miscellaneous Correspondence
Series VI. History
General
Manhattan Project
Soviet and International Science and Intrigue
Series VII. Certificates and Awards
Series VIII. Oversize
Series IX. Multimedia
Videos
Tape recordings
CONTAINER LIST FOR THE FIRST ADDITION TO THE COLLECTION
- Series I. Teaching
  - Courses
    - Miscellaneous Papers and Calculations and Class Problems (Box 61, Folder 1-3)
    - Course notes: Quantum Mechanics for Seniors (443) (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Problems for Physics 574 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Notes/Miscellany for Physics 574 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Problems for Physics 574 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Notes for course: Advanced Quantum Mechanics 491 (1946) (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Course Notes for Mechanics (Graduate Course)(1946-51) (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Notes/Calculations on Relativity course (ca. 1956) (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - Course notes: Electrodynamics (Graduate Course)(1951) (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Course notes for Statistical Mechanics (1952) (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Notes/Calculations/Problems for course on High Energy Physics (1956 or 1957) (Box 61, Folder 19-21)
    - Notes for course: Mechanics for Freshmen (107) (Fall, 1957) (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Course notes: Quantum Mechanics II (1958) (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Notes/Calculations for course on High Energy Physics (1959) (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - Course notes for Quantum Mechanics (1956, 1958) (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Course notes for Quantum Mechanics (1962) (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Problems for Physics 574 (1967, earlier) (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Textbook notes for Quantum Mechanics (1968) (Box 61, Folder 30-31)
    - Notes, etc. for Physics 572 (1968) (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - Notes/Exams for Physics 574 - Intermediate Quantum Mechanics (1961, 1963) (Box 61, Folder 33-34)
    - Problems for Classes (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Notes/Class work, etc. Electric Conduction, etc. (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Physics 561 - Final Grades (Box 69, Folder 44)
    - High Energy Phenomenon (1952) (Box 73)
    - Lecture Notes, Physics 574: Atoms (Box 76, Folder 25-27)
    - Quantum Mechanics, Physics 572 (Box 76, Folder 30-31)
    - Nuclear Matter Lecture Course (Box 79, Folder 36-37)
    - Physics 431: Mechanics for Seniors and Non-physics Graduate Students, includes Special Relativity, Shock Waves (Box 82, Folder 37-38)
  - Exams
    - Exam A for Ph.D. Candidacy (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Ph.D. Candidacy Exam (1956-69) (Box 61, Folder 28)
  - Students
    - Notes on Grad Students (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Old Student Problems (ca. 1961) (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Reid Potentials (1963) and correspondence (1971-72) (Box 79, Folder 43)
    - Baranger thesis: "Relativistic Corrections to the Lamb Shift," including calculations by Bethe and Feynman (Box 79, Folder 52-53)
    - Klemperer thesis: "A Study of Spread-F Echoes from the Ionosphere" (1962) (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - David Harding thesis (1983) (Box 87, Folder 29-32)
    - David Howard Kaplan thesis (1983) (Box 87, Folder 34-36)
    - Goldstone, Jeffrey (1956-65) (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Student pictures - classes of 1978-81 (Box 92, Folder 42)
  - Physics Department
    - Physics Department Miscellany (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Admissions/Financial Aid - Alumni (Box 67, Folder 27-31)
    - Alumni/Financial Aid: Loan Plan (Box 67, Folder 32)
    - Academic Responsibilities of the Faculty (1968) (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence to Velma Ray (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies Phone Logs (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Photon-Lepton Conference (1983) (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - Velma Ray Time Cards (1981-89) (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Velma Ray Time Cards (Box 95, Folder 39)
    - Telephone sheets (Box 92, Folder 38-39)
    - Physics Colloquium notices (Box 92, Folder 41)
    - Physics Colloquium notices (Box 92, Folder 43)
    - Secretary's Notebook (1976-78) (Box 96, Folder 27)
  - Faculty Appointments/Promotions
    - Kogut, Promotion to Tenure? (1978) (Box 82, Folder 36)
    - Kenneth G. Wilson (1963) (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Jean Pestieau (1968) (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Assistant Professor of Physics Search (1984) (Box 87, Folder 40)
    - Selection Committee of Professors-at-Large (1971) (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Post-doctoral Fellowship Applicants
    - G. Bhattacharya (1978-81) (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - G. Bhanot (1980) (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - A. Longhitano (1980-81) (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - D'Hoker, Eric (1983-84) (Box 87, Folder 41)
    - Tsokos, Kyriakos (1984) (Box 87, Folder 45)
    - Marko Jaric (1985) (Box 88, Folder 25)
    - Ed Baron (1986) (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Cornell University Information
    - Doctoral Thesis and Advanced Degree Requirements (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Travel Expense Accounting (1983-86) (Box 87, Folder 43)
    - Travel Expense Accounting (1987-89) (Box 89, Folder 16)
    - Travel Expense Accounting (1990-91) (Box 89, Folder 38)
- Series II. Research
  - Grant Proposals
    - Research Proposal to the National Science Foundation: Theoretical Nuclear and Elementary Particle Physics (1972), Bethe is Principal Investigator (Box 96, Folder 21)
    - Research Proposal to the National Science Foundation: Theoretical Nuclear and Elementary Particle Physics (1974), Bethe is Principal Investigator (Box 96, Folder 22)
    - Research Proposal to the National Science Foundation: Theoretical Nuclear and Elementary Particle Physics (1976), Bethe is not Principal Investigator (Box 96, Folder 23-25)
    - Research Proposal to the National Science Foundation: Theoretical Nuclear and Elementary Particle Physics (1983), Bethe is not Principal Investigator (Box 96, Folder 36)
    - Research Proposal to the National Science Foundation: Theoretical Nuclear and Elementary Particle Physics (1984), Bethe is not Principal Investigator (Box 96, Folder 37)
    - Research Proposal to the National Science Foundation: Theoretical Nuclear and Elementary Particle Physics (1982), Bethe is not Principal Investigator (Box 96, Folder 30)
    - Research Proposal to the National Science Foundation: Theoretical Nuclear and Elementary Particle Physics (1985-86), Bethe is not Principal Investigator (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Notes and Calculations
    Also includes data printouts
    - Seminar Notes (Box 61, Folder 4-7)
    - Notes/Calculations: Fermi Theory (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Notes/Calculations: Electron Scattering (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Notes/Calculations and Graphs (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Notes/Calculations: Absorption Strength of Electrons (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Notes/Calculations/Miscellaneous Plots: Modification of Fermi Theory of Stopping (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Notes/Calculations: Diffusion of Electrons (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Notes/Calculations: Equation of State, Kirkwood Method, etc. (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Notes/Calculations: Nuclear Theory; Statistical; Quadropole Moments of Heavy Nuclei (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Notes/Calculations/Miscellaneous: Range Energy in Hydrogen (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Notes/Calculations: "Calculations of Amplitude Form Factor" (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Notes/Calculations: Magnetic Scattering of Neutrons (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Notes/Calculations: Proton-Proton Reaction (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Notes/Calculations: Electron Physics miscellany (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Notes/Calculations: Theory of Self-Energy for Scalar Equations (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence/Manuscript on Magnet Calculations (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - Calculations for Absorption of X-Rays (Box 62, Folder 20)
    - Calculations on Meson Theory (Box 62, Folder 21)
    - Calculations: Electron Spectrums (Box 62, Folder 22)
    - Notes/Calculations: Neutron Resonance Levels (Box 62, Folder 24)
    - Notes/Calculations: Diffusion of Neutrons (Box 62, Folder 25)
    - Notes/Calculations: Determination of Width (Box 62, Folder 26)
    - Tables and Calculations: Neutron-Nucleus Collision Cross-sections (Box 62, Folder 27)
    - Notes/Calculations: Multiple Scattering of Neutrons (Box 62, Folder 28)
    - Notes/Calculations: Absorption for Incidence from All Sides (Box 62, Folder 29)
    - Notes/Calculations: Oblique Incidence and Ratio of the Selective and the Temperature Absorption (Box 62, Folder 30)
    - Notes/Calculations: Miscellaneous Electron Physics (Box 62, Folder 31)
    - Notes/Calculations: Diffusion of Neutrons (Box 62, Folder 32)
    - Notes/Calculations: Scattering (Box 62, Folder 33)
    - Notes/Calculations: Diffusion of Neutrons (Box 62, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous Notes/Plots/Calculations on Boron Absorption-Resonance (Box 62, Folder 35)
    - Notes/Calculations: Magnetic Scattering of Neutrons (Box 62, Folder 36)
    - Notes/Calculations: Lane Reflection from Calcite (Box 62, Folder 37)
    - Notes/Calculations: Slow Neutron Capture in Hydrogen (Box 62, Folder 38)
    - Notes/Calculations: Miscellaneous Degeneracy (Box 62, Folder 39)
    - Notes/Calculations: Non-degenerate State (Box 62, Folder 40)
    - Notes/Calculations: The Neutron Core Plus Relativistically Degenerate envelope (Box 62, Folder 41)
    - Notes/Calculations: The Equation of State (Box 62, Folder 42)
    - Calculations: Radiation from Volume Waves (Box 62, Folder 43)
    - Calculations: Nuclear Reactions (Box 62, Folder 44)
    - Notes/Calculations: Electron Physics (Box 62, Folder 45)
    - Notes/Calculations: "Stragglin, etc." (Box 62, Folder 46)
    - Notes/Calculations: Electron Physics (Box 62, Folder 47)
    - Notes/Calculations on Klassische Stosstheorie (Box 62, Folder 48)
    - Calculations: Potential for d-electrons (Box 62, Folder 49)
    - Calculations: Electron Orbitals (Box 62, Folder 50)
    - Calculations on Electron Physics (Box 62, Folder 51)
    - Calculations on Electron Physics (Field and Spin) (Box 62, Folder 52)
    - Calculations on Electron Physics (Box 62, Folder 53)
    - Calculations on Electron Physics (Box 62, Folder 55)
    - Calculations on Electron Physics (Transitions) (Box 62, Folder 56)